I'm an MIT professor.
[AI] 我是麻省理工学院的教授。
but I do not design buildings or computer systems.
[AI] 但我不设计建筑物或计算机系统。
Rather. I build body parts.
[AI] 相当地我制造身体部位。
bionic legs that augment human walking and running.
[AI] 增强人类行走和跑步能力的仿生腿。
In 1982. I was in a mountain-climbing accident.
[AI] 1982年。我出了一次登山事故。
and both of my legs had to be amputated due to tissue damage from frostbite.
[AI] 由于冻伤造成的组织损伤，我的双腿不得不截肢。
Here. you can see my legs:
[AI] 在这里你可以看到我的腿：
24 sensors. six microprocessors and muscle-tendon-like actuators.
[AI] 24个传感器。六个微处理器和肌腱状执行器。
I'm basically a bunch of nuts and bolts from the knee down.
[AI] 我基本上是膝盖以下的一堆螺母和螺栓。
But with this advanced bionic technology.
[AI] 但是有了这种先进的仿生技术。
I can skip. dance and run.
[AI] 我可以跳过。跳舞和跑步。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
I'm a bionic man. but I'm not yet a cyborg.
[AI] 我是一个仿生人。但我还不是一个电子人。
When I think about moving my legs.
[AI] 当我想到移动我的腿。
neural signals from my central nervous system
[AI] 来自中枢神经系统的神经信号
pass through my nerves
[AI] 穿过我的神经
and activate muscles within my residual limbs.
[AI] 激活我残肢的肌肉。
Artificial electrodes sense these signals.
[AI] 人造电极感应这些信号。
and small computers in the bionic limb
[AI] 以及仿生肢体中的小型计算机
decode my nerve pulses into my intended movement patterns.
[AI] 把我的神经脉冲解码成我想要的运动模式。
Stated simply.
[AI] 简单地说。
when I think about moving.
[AI] 当我想到搬家的时候。
that command is communicated to the synthetic part of my body.
[AI] 这个命令被传送到我身体的合成部位。
However. those computers can't input information into my nervous system.
[AI] 然而那些电脑不能把信息输入我的神经系统。
When I touch and move my synthetic limbs.
[AI] 当我触摸和移动我的人造肢体时。
I do not experience normal touch and movement sensations.
[AI] 我没有正常的触摸和运动感觉。
If I were a cyborg and could feel my legs
[AI] 如果我是一个机器人，能感觉到我的腿
via small computers inputting information into my nervous system.
[AI] 通过小型计算机将信息输入我的神经系统。
it would fundamentally change. I believe.
[AI] 这将从根本上改变。我相信。
my relationship to my synthetic body.
[AI] 我和我的人造身体的关系。
Today. I can't feel my legs.
[AI] 今天我腿麻了
and because of that.
[AI] 正因为如此。
my legs are separate tools from my mind and my body.
[AI] 我的腿是与我的思想和身体分开的工具。
They're not part of me.
[AI] 他们不是我的一部分。
I believe that if I were a cyborg and could feel my legs.
[AI] 我相信如果我是一个机器人，能感觉到我的腿。
they would become part of me. part of self.
[AI] 他们会成为我的一部分。自我的一部分。
At MIT. we're thinking about NeuroEmbodied Design.
[AI] 在麻省理工学院。我们正在考虑神经体现设计。
In this design process.
[AI] 在这个设计过程中。
the designer designs human flesh and bone. the biological body itself.
[AI] 设计师设计人的骨肉。生物体本身。
along with synthetics to enhance the bidirectional communication
[AI] 结合综合手段，加强双向沟通
between the nervous system and the built world.
[AI] 在神经系统和人造世界之间。
NeuroEmbodied Design is a methodology to create cyborg function.
[AI] 神经体现设计是一种创造电子人功能的方法。
In this design process. designers contemplate a future
[AI] 在这个设计过程中。设计师展望未来
in which technology no longer compromises separate.
[AI] 在这种情况下，技术不再妥协于独立。
lifeless tools from our minds and our bodies.
[AI] 我们的头脑和身体中没有生命的工具。
a future in which technology has been carefully integrated
[AI] 技术被仔细整合的未来
within our nature.
[AI] 在我们的天性中。
a world in which what is biological and what is not.
[AI] 一个什么是生物的，什么不是的世界。
what is human and what is not.
[AI] 什么是人，什么不是人。
what is nature and what is not
[AI] 什么是自然，什么不是
will be forever blurred.
[AI] 将永远模糊。
That future will provide humanity new bodies.
[AI] 这一未来将为人类提供新的身体。
NeuroEmbodied Design will extend our nervous systems
[AI] 神经体现设计将扩展我们的神经系统
into the synthetic world.
[AI] 进入合成世界。
and the synthetic world into us.
[AI] 和合成世界进入我们。
fundamentally changing who we are.
[AI] 从根本上改变我们是谁。
By designing the biological body to better communicate
[AI] 通过设计生物机体来更好地沟通
with the built design world.
[AI] 随着设计世界的建立。
humanity will end disability in this 21st century
[AI] 人类将在21世纪结束残疾
and establish the scientific and technological basis
[AI] 建立科学技术基础
for human augmentation.
[AI] 用于人类增强。
extending human capability beyond innate. physiological levels.
[AI] 将人的能力扩展到先天能力之外。生理水平。
cognitively. emotionally and physically.
[AI] 认知的。在情感上和身体上。
There are many ways in which to build new bodies across scale.
[AI] 有许多方法可以跨规模构建新机构。
from the biomolecular to the scale of tissues and organs.
[AI] 从生物分子到组织和器官的尺度。
Today. I want to talk about one area of NeuroEmbodied Design.
[AI] 今天我想谈谈神经体现设计的一个领域。
in which the body's tissues are manipulated and sculpted
[AI] 身体组织在其中被操纵和雕刻
using surgical and regenerative processes.
[AI] 使用手术和再生过程。
The current amputation paradigm
[AI] 当前的截肢范式
hasn't changed fundamentally since the US Civil War
[AI] 自美国内战以来没有发生根本性的变化
and has grown obsolete in light of dramatic advancements
[AI] 并且随着戏剧性的进步而变得过时
in actuators. control systems and neural interfacing technologies.
[AI] 在执行器中。控制系统和神经接口技术。
A major deficiency is the lack of dynamic muscle interactions
[AI] 一个主要缺陷是缺乏动态肌肉互动
for control and proprioception.
[AI] 用于控制和本体感觉。
What is proprioception?
[AI] 什么是本体感觉？
When you flex your ankle. muscles in the front of your leg contract.
[AI] 当你弯曲脚踝时。腿部前部的肌肉收缩。
simultaneously stretching muscles in the back of your leg.
[AI] 同时伸展腿部后部的肌肉。
The opposite happens when you extend your ankle.
[AI] 当你伸展脚踝时，情况正好相反。
Here. muscles in the back of your leg contract.
[AI] 在这里腿部后部的肌肉收缩。
stretching muscles in the front.
[AI] 伸展前面的肌肉。
When these muscles flex and extend.
[AI] 当这些肌肉伸缩时。
biological sensors within the muscle tendons
[AI] 肌腱内的生物传感器
send information through nerves to the brain.
[AI] 通过神经向大脑发送信息。
This is how we're able to feel where our feet are
[AI] 这就是我们能够感觉脚在哪里的方式
without seeing them with our eyes.
[AI] 而不是用我们的眼睛看他们。
The current amputation paradigm breaks these dynamic muscle relationships.
[AI] 当前的截肢模式打破了这些动态的肌肉关系。
and in so doing eliminates normal proprioceptive sensations.
[AI] 这样做可以消除正常的本体感觉。
Consequently. a standard artificial limb
[AI] 因此标准假肢
cannot feed back information into the nervous system
[AI] 无法将信息反馈到神经系统
about where the prosthesis is in space.
[AI] 关于假体在太空中的位置。
The patient therefore cannot sense and feel
[AI] 因此，患者无法感觉到
the positions and movements of the prosthetic joint
[AI] 假肢关节的位置和运动
without seeing it with their eyes.
[AI] 而不是用他们的眼睛看。
My legs were amputated using this Civil War-era methodology.
[AI] 我的腿是用内战时期的方法截肢的。
I can feel my feet. I can feel them right now
[AI] 我能感觉到我的脚。我现在能感觉到
as a phantom awareness.
[AI] 作为一种幻影意识。
But when I try to move them. I cannot.
[AI] 但当我试图移动它们时。我不能。
It feels like they're stuck inside rigid ski boots.
[AI] 感觉就像被卡在坚硬的滑雪靴里。
To solve these problems.
[AI] 解决这些问题。
at MIT. we invented the agonist-antagonist myoneural interface.
[AI] 在麻省理工学院。我们发明了激动剂拮抗剂肌神经界面。
or AMI. for short.
[AI] 或者阿美族。简而言之。
The AMI is a method to connect nerves within the residuum
[AI] AMI是一种连接残余体内神经的方法
to an external. bionic prosthesis.
[AI] 到外部。仿生假体。
How is the AMI designed. and how does it work?
[AI] AMI是如何设计的。它是如何工作的？
The AMI comprises two muscles that are surgically connected.
[AI] AMI由两块通过手术连接的肌肉组成。
an agonist linked to an antagonist.
[AI] 与对手有联系的激动剂。
When the agonist contracts upon electrical activation.
[AI] 当激动剂在电激活后收缩时。
it stretches the antagonist.
[AI] 它拉长了对手。
This muscle dynamic interaction
[AI] 这是肌肉的动态相互作用
causes biological sensors within the muscle tendon
[AI] 导致肌腱内的生物传感器
to send information through the nerve to the central nervous system.
[AI] 通过神经向中枢神经系统发送信息。
relating information on the muscle tendon's length. speed and force.
[AI] 关于肌腱长度的相关信息。速度和力量。
This is how muscle tendon proprioception works.
[AI] 这就是肌腱本体感觉的工作原理。
and it's the primary way we. as humans.
[AI] 这是我们的主要方式。作为人类。
can feel and sense the positions. movements and forces on our limbs.
[AI] 能够感觉和感觉到位置。我们四肢的运动和力量。
When a limb is amputated.
[AI] 截肢时。
the surgeon connects these opposing muscles within the residuum
[AI] 外科医生在残余体内连接这些相对的肌肉
to create an AMI.
[AI] 创建一个AMI。
Now. multiple AMI constructs can be created
[AI] 现在可以创建多个AMI构造
for the control and sensation of multiple prosthetic joints.
[AI] 用于控制和感觉多个假肢关节。
Artificial electrodes are then placed on each AMI muscle.
[AI] 然后在每个AMI肌肉上放置人工电极。
and small computers within the bionic limb decode those signals
[AI] 仿生肢体内的小型计算机对这些信号进行解码
to control powerful motors on the bionic limb.
[AI] 控制仿生肢体上的强大马达。
When the bionic limb moves.
[AI] 当仿生肢体移动时。
the AMI muscles move back and forth.
[AI] AMI肌肉来回运动。
sending signals through the nerve to the brain.
[AI] 通过神经向大脑发送信号。
enabling a person wearing the prosthesis to experience natural sensations
[AI] 使佩戴假肢的人能够体验自然感觉
of positions and movements of the prosthesis.
[AI] 假肢的位置和运动。
Can these tissue-design principles be used in an actual human being?
[AI] 这些组织设计原则能用于实际的人类吗？
A few years ago. my good friend Jim Ewing -- of 34 years --
[AI] 几年前。我的好朋友吉姆·尤因，34岁--
reached out to me for help.
[AI] 向我求助。
Jim was in an a terrible climbing accident.
[AI] 吉姆在一次可怕的攀登事故中。
He fell 50 feet in the Cayman Islands
[AI] 他在开曼群岛坠落了50英尺
when his rope failed to catch him hitting the ground's surface.
[AI] 当他的绳子没能抓住他时，他撞到了地面。
He suffered many. many injuries:
[AI] 他遭受了许多痛苦。许多人受伤：
punctured lungs and many broken bones.
[AI] 刺破了肺和许多骨折。
After his accident. he dreamed of returning to his chosen sport
[AI] 在他的事故之后。他梦想着回到他选择的运动
of mountain climbing.
[AI] 我喜欢爬山。
but how might this be possible?
[AI] 但这怎么可能呢？
The answer was Team Cyborg.
[AI] 答案是电子人小组。
a team of surgeons. scientists and engineers
[AI] 一队外科医生。科学家和工程师
assembled at MIT to rebuild Jim back to his former climbing prowess.
[AI] 在麻省理工学院集合，让吉姆重获昔日的攀岩本领。
Team member Dr. Matthew Carty amputated Jim's badly damaged leg
[AI] 队员马修·卡蒂医生截肢了吉姆严重受损的腿
at Brigham and Women's Hospital in Boston.
[AI] 在波士顿的百翰女子医院。
using the AMI surgical procedure.
[AI] 使用AMI手术程序。
Tendon pulleys were created and attached to Jim's tibia bone
[AI] 肌腱滑轮被制造出来并连接到吉姆的胫骨上
to reconnect the opposing muscles.
[AI] 重新连接相对的肌肉。
The AMI procedure reestablished the neural link
[AI] AMI程序重建了神经联系
between Jim's ankle-foot muscles and his brain.
[AI] 在吉姆的脚踝肌肉和大脑之间。
When Jim moves his phantom limb.
[AI] 当吉姆移动他的幻肢时。
the reconnected muscles move in dynamic pairs.
[AI] 重新连接的肌肉成对运动。
causing signals of proprioception to pass through nerves to the brain.
[AI] 使本体感觉信号通过神经传递到大脑。
so Jim experiences normal sensations with ankle-foot positions and movements.
[AI] 因此，吉姆在踝足的位置和运动中有正常的感觉。
even when blindfolded.
[AI] 即使蒙着眼睛。
Here's Jim at the MIT laboratory after his surgeries.
[AI] 这是吉姆手术后在麻省理工学院实验室。
We electrically linked Jim's AMI muscles. via the electrodes.
[AI] 我们用电把吉姆的肌肉连接起来。通过电极。
to a bionic limb.
[AI] 到仿生肢体。
and Jim quickly learned how to move the bionic limb
[AI] 吉姆很快就学会了如何移动仿生肢体
in four distinct ankle-foot movement directions.
[AI] 在四个不同的踝足运动方向。
We were excited by these results. but then Jim stood up.
[AI] 我们对这些结果感到兴奋。但是吉姆站了起来。
and what occurred was truly remarkable.
[AI] 发生的事情真的很了不起。
All the natural biomechanics mediated by the central nervous system
[AI] 所有由中枢神经系统介导的自然生物力学
emerged via the synthetic limb
[AI] 通过合成肢体出现
as an involuntary. reflexive action.
[AI] 作为一种非自愿的行为。反射性动作。
All the intricacies of foot placement during stair ascent --
[AI] 在爬楼梯时，脚的位置非常复杂--
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
emerged before our eyes.
[AI] 出现在我们眼前。
Here's Jim descending steps.
[AI] 吉姆在下台阶。
reaching with his bionic toe to the next stair tread.
[AI] 用他的仿生脚趾到达下一个楼梯踏板。
automatically exhibiting natural motions
[AI] 自动显示自然运动的
without him even trying to move his limb.
[AI] 他甚至都不想动他的四肢。
Because Jim's central nervous system is receiving the proprioceptive signals.
[AI] 因为吉姆的中枢神经系统正在接收本体感觉信号。
it knows exactly how to control the synthetic limb in a natural way.
[AI] 它确切地知道如何以自然的方式控制合成肢体。
Now. Jim moves and behaves as if the synthetic limb is part of him.
[AI] 现在吉姆的动作和行为就好像人造肢体是他的一部分。
For example. one day in the lab.
[AI] 例如有一天在实验室。
he accidentally stepped on a roll of electrical tape.
[AI] 他不小心踩到了一卷电工胶带。
Now. what do you do when something's stuck to your shoe?
[AI] 现在当有东西粘在你的鞋子上时你会怎么做？
You don't reach down like this; it's way too awkward.
[AI] 你不能像这样俯身；太尴尬了。
Instead. you shake it off.
[AI] 相反你把它甩掉。
and that's exactly what Jim did
[AI] 吉姆就是这么做的
after being neurally connected to the limb for just a few hours.
[AI] 在与肢体神经连接了几个小时后。
What was most interesting to me
[AI] 我最感兴趣的是什么
is what Jim was telling us he was experiencing.
[AI] 这就是吉姆告诉我们他所经历的。
He said. "The robot became part of me."
[AI] 他说。“机器人成了我的一部分。”
Jim Ewing: The morning after the first time I was attached to the robot.
[AI] 吉姆·尤因：我第一次接触机器人后的第二天早上。
my daughter came downstairs and asked me how it felt to be a cyborg.
[AI] 我女儿下楼来问我做一个机器人的感觉如何。
and my answer was that I didn't feel like a cyborg.
[AI] 我的回答是，我觉得自己不像一个电子人。
I felt like I had my leg.
[AI] 我觉得我有腿了。
and it wasn't that I was attached to the robot
[AI] 并不是因为我喜欢机器人
so much as the robot was attached to me.
[AI] 就像机器人附在我身上一样。
and the robot became part of me.
[AI] 机器人成为了我的一部分。
It became my leg pretty quickly.
[AI] 它很快就变成了我的腿。
Hugh Herr: Thank you.
[AI] 休·赫尔：谢谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
By connecting Jim's nervous system bidirectionally
[AI] 通过双向连接Jim的神经系统
to his synthetic limb.
[AI] 他的假肢。
neurological embodiment was achieved.
[AI] 实现了神经学的具体化。
I hypothesized that because Jim can think and move his synthetic limb.
[AI] 我假设这是因为吉姆能思考和移动他的合成肢体。
and because he can feel those movements within his nervous system.
[AI] 因为他能感觉到神经系统的运动。
the prosthesis is no longer a separate tool.
[AI] 假体不再是一个单独的工具。
but an integral part of Jim. an integral part of his body.
[AI] 但这是吉姆不可分割的一部分。他身体不可分割的一部分。
Because of this neurological embodiment. Jim doesn't feel like a cyborg.
[AI] 因为这个神经学的化身。吉姆觉得自己不像个电子人。
He feels like he just has his leg back.
[AI] 他觉得自己的腿好像又回来了。
that he has his body back.
[AI] 他恢复了他的身体。
Now I'm often asked
[AI] 现在经常有人问我
when I'm going to be neurally linked to my synthetic limbs bidirectionally.
[AI] 当我要双向连接到我的合成肢体时。
when I'm going to become a cyborg.
[AI] 当我要成为一个电子人的时候。
The truth is. I'm hesitant to become a cyborg.
[AI] 事实是。我不想成为一个电子人。
Before my legs were amputated. I was a terrible student.
[AI] 在我的腿被截肢之前。我是个糟糕的学生。
I got D's and often F's in school.
[AI] 我在学校得了D，经常得F。
Then. after my limbs were amputated.
[AI] 然后我的四肢被截肢后。
I suddenly became an MIT professor.
[AI] 我突然成了麻省理工学院的教授。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
Now I'm worried that once I'm neurally connected to my limbs once again.
[AI] 现在我担心一旦我的神经再次与四肢相连。
my brain will remap back to its not-so-bright self.
[AI] 我的大脑将重新映射回它不那么明亮的自我。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
But you know what. that's OK. because at MIT. I already have tenure.
[AI] 但你知道吗。没关系。因为在麻省理工学院。我已经有任期了。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
I believe the reach of NeuroEmbodied Design
[AI] 我相信神经体现设计的影响力
will extend far beyond limb replacement
[AI] 将远远超出肢体置换
and will carry humanity into realms
[AI] 并将把人类带入世界
that fundamentally redefine human potential.
[AI] 这从根本上重新定义了人类的潜力。
In this 21st century.
[AI] 在这个21世纪。
designers will extend the nervous system into powerfully strong exoskeletons
[AI] 设计师们将把神经系统扩展成强大的外骨骼
that humans can control and feel with their minds.
[AI] 人类可以用他们的思想控制和感觉。
Muscles within the body can be reconfigured
[AI] 身体内的肌肉可以重新配置
for the control of powerful motors.
[AI] 用于控制大功率电机。
and to feel and sense exoskeletal movements.
[AI] 感觉和感知外骨骼运动。
augmenting humans' strength. jumping height and running speed.
[AI] 增强人类的力量。跳跃高度和奔跑速度。
In this 21st century. I believe humans will become superheroes.
[AI] 在这个21世纪。我相信人类会成为超级英雄。
Humans may also extend their bodies
[AI] 人类也可以伸展身体
into non-anthropomorphic structures. such as wings.
[AI] 进入非拟人结构。比如翅膀。
controlling and feeling each wing movement within the nervous system.
[AI] 控制和感觉神经系统中的每一个翅膀运动。
Leonardo da Vinci said. "When once you have tasted flight.
[AI] 达芬奇说。“当你尝过飞行的滋味。
you will forever walk the earth with your eyes turned skyward.
[AI] 你将永远走在地球上，眼睛转向天空。
for there you have been and there you will always long to return."
[AI] 因为你曾经去过那里，你将永远渴望回到那里。"
During the twilight years of this century.
[AI] 在本世纪的暮年。
I believe humans will be unrecognizable in morphology and dynamics
[AI] 我相信人类在形态和动力学上是无法辨认的
from what we are today.
[AI] 从我们今天的情况来看。
Humanity will take flight and soar.
[AI] 人类将飞翔、翱翔。
Jim Ewing fell to earth and was badly broken.
[AI] 吉姆·尤因摔倒在地，严重受伤。
but his eyes turned skyward. where he always longed to return.
[AI] 但他的眼睛转向天空。他一直渴望回到那里。
After his accident. he not only dreamed to walk again.
[AI] 在他的事故之后。他不仅梦想再次行走。
but also to return to his chosen sport of mountain climbing.
[AI] 但也要回到他选择的登山运动。
At MIT. Team Cyborg built Jim a specialized limb for the vertical world.
[AI] 在麻省理工学院。机器人小组为吉姆建造了一个垂直世界专用的肢体。
a brain-controlled leg with full position and movement sensations.
[AI] 由大脑控制的腿，有完整的姿势和运动感觉。
Using this technology. Jim returned to the Cayman Islands.
[AI] 使用这项技术。吉姆回到了开曼群岛。
the site of his accident.
[AI] 他出事的地点。
rebuilt as a cyborg to climb skyward once again.
[AI] 重建成一个电子人，再次向天空攀爬。
(Crashing waves)
[AI] （巨浪）
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
Ladies and gentlemen. Jim Ewing. the first cyborg rock climber.
[AI] 女士们，先生们。吉姆·尤因。第一个电子人攀岩者。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）